Crooked the road
and the [music] one
driving.
25 [music]
years
I know you've been unraveling.
Tell me, [music] why did you run
run past the dogs and the horses?
[music and singing]
Now you find [music] yourself here
past the deuce and don't serve your
choices. [music]
But if you're leaving,
no, I'll [music] stay beside [singing]
that telephone line.
[music]
And tomorrow
we might steal the sun from underneath
[music and singing] our eyes.
[music]
M
tennis courts when I was yours. Late
night releasing sacred flows got [music]
me believing a little more [singing]
that this pain will run its course in
the morning. Saw you there holding out
your hand. If I grab it, [music] know
that I care. Cuz darkness don't look
good. But if you're leaving,
no, I'll stay beside that telephone
line.
[music]
And tomorrow
we might steal the sun
[singing and music] from underneath our
eyes.
Day breaks [music and singing] sorrow,
but I still feel the edge [music] of
this cold night.
[music]
But [singing] next to you,
I lay [music] softly on this hard
ground.
[music]
But if you're leaving,
no, I'll stand [music and singing] aside
that telephone line.
[music]
And tomorrow
we might [music] steal the sun from
underneath our eyes.
[music]
Day breaks sorrow,
but I still feel [singing]
the [music] edge of this cold night.
Next to you, [music]
I [singing] live softly
on [music] this hard ground.
Next to you,
[music]
I lay softly
on this heart.
[cheering and applause]
[cheering]
[applause]
>> Thank you so much.
Uh hello Tiny Desk. Uh I'm Monrovia.
It's a pleasure uh of all of our lives
to be up here with you guys today. Uh
something we've all watched and and
yearned to be on uh as artists and
singers. Uh that last song you heard was
Crooked the Road. And uh you know, we
released an album this year called
Bloodline. And uh this title track of
the song, it's probably one of the most
important songs I've written in a long
time. And it meant so much to me to
because of my journey and where I've
come from. You know, I kind of grew up
never feeling like I was belonging to
any group, you know, in those things
coming from Africa. And uh it was hard.
I think it led me to a lot of different
places, a lot of uh of hurt along the
way. But in writing this song for this
project, you know, I kind of got to heal
a bit and truly understand that, you
know, wherever you're from in the world
and wherever you move to, your people
are always with you. You know, they're
in the gifts that you have. and uh uh it
brought me a lot of peace and joy to uh
to put this song out. So uh this one's
called Bloodline, and I hope it means
something to you if you if you're
missing home or you've come a long way
from there.
1 2 3 4. Thou [singing]
my great father
and I thy true [music] son.
10,000 [music]
roads
I've walked on my own.
Further I [singing and music] go,
I'm closer to my goals.
Came [music] a long way,
can't find my bloodline.
[music and singing]
My name
still [music and singing] ties my
bloodline.
Still [singing]
m
my [music] bloodline.
Still
[music]
my bloodline. [singing]
Is all what I [music] know.
Call him my own. [music]
Ooh.
>> [music]
>> Ooh.
[music]
Carry the song
of people who've come and gone. They say
[music]
play [singing]
on, play on, play [music and singing]
on.
Give a long way.
Can't [music] find my bloodline.
My name
still [music and singing] ties my blood.
Still
[music] my blood.
Still [music and singing]
my blood.
Still
my blood. [music]
my blood [music]
is all what I know.
Say [singing and music] it. So
call him out.
[music]
[applause and cheering]
Thank you.
[applause]
Every day history is being made. It's
hard to feel like you're not a part of
that. And uh the important thing is
we're always embers of our time when we
move into the future of things. And it's
important to tell history the way it was
and no matter how hard or terrifying it
can seem. Uh it's important because when
we tell the things as they h as they
happened, uh we make sure that these
things don't happen in the world that we
live in today. And uh so please make
sure to yeah to just to find the truth
of a thing and make sure it's relayed.
And uh it's a beautiful thing to to hold
that responsibility in the moments that
we live. This song's called Somewhere
Down in Georgia.
[music]
Old [music] ghosts
still walk [singing] alone.
[music]
Cotton fields,
certain [music] parking [singing] lots,
steel and stone.
Can't hide [music and singing] these
stains.
History still grows
through [music] the cracks when it
rains.
Rain over [music and singing] the past
and build it high. I'll never fall under
[music] magnolia leaves. I felt their
pain. She told me all these embers.
Still remember
somewhere down in Georgia.
Ooh. [music]
Ooh.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Don't
[music] let the sun [singing] go down on
me.
[music]
[singing] Bear in love.
A violent [singing]
[music] history.
Red blood [music]
[singing]
down every street. [music]
They [singing]
want
[music]
[singing]
to see
>> [music]
>> That curse still in Mississippi until
still smiling. [music]
Country's full of crows and tin men. One
love without a [singing] heart in the
land. Times are like the walls of
Jericho. Raise your voice. I begin
[music] to go. 10 toes with many at the
ready. And as it comes, stay steady.
Take [music] the side away. The devil
see.
Oh, you better run. [music]
Oh, you better run before the [music]
bad man comes.
Before the bad man [singing] comes. Oh,
you better [music] run before the bad
man comes. Oh, [singing] you better
[music] run before the bad man comes.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Oh, you better [music and singing] run
before the bad man comes.
Oh, you [music] better run before the
bad man comes.
Oh, [music and singing] you better run
before the bad man comes.
Oh, [singing and music] you better run
Oh, [singing] you better run before the
[music] bad man comes in the
run. [music]
I've been there. [singing]
>> Oh, you better run. [music]
>> I' been for the
when he came. [singing]
>> Oh, you better run. But the [music] bad
man comes.
[cheering]
[applause]
Thank you. [applause]
>> [cheering]
[applause]
>> Uh, thank yeah, you can keep on
clapping. Give a [music] big hand to
this beautiful band. They're friends of
mine. It's been amazing to sing with
them. So, yeah, thank you for singing
with me, everybody.
Yeah, in these times [music] we live in,
yeah, just make sure to take care of
each other. Uh, this song is for those
that are stepping outside, you know, not
[music] afraid. And, uh, it's meant to
encourage you. You got to have joy when
you're standing up to something. And I
hope this song can be a part of your
life as you go and stand [music] up for
the things that need to be stood up for.
This song's called Heavy Foot. Thank you
so much for your time.
Did you [music] feel the sound of the
bell? Did you wish your family well?
Times ain't [music and singing] the same
in the neighborhood. Got the parents all
going through hell. Cuz the guns keep
flying [music] off the shelf.
Did you see the man on the street just
fighting for a meal [music] to eat?
You could ride him off as a [singing]
lunatic, but it could have [music] been
you or me if we didn't ever find our
feet.
Love me now.
Hold me down.
And the government [music] stays on
[singing] heavy foot. And they try to
keep us all down. No, [music] they never
going to keep us all down. [singing]
Did you see the birds in the cage on the
highway working like slaves? It's a con,
it's a ruse, it's a [music] gas light.
Find it funny how far we came for them
to go and change [music] the name.
Did you see the man on the screen? Just
a puppet though you never see the
streets.
Calling it a war, not a genocide.
[music] Telling us it isn't what it
seems. Hey, that's a different kind of
gummy.
[music]
Hold me down.
And the government stays
[singing and music] on heavy foot. And
they try to keep us all down.
Me down.
Hold me down.
[music] And the government stays on
everybody. They try to keep us all down.
No, they never going to keep us all
down. [singing]
me [music] now.
Hold me down. [music]
Love me now.
Hold me down.
[music] And they try [singing] to keep
us all down. No, they never going to
keep us all down.
[music]
>> Thank [cheering] you so much. Fantastic.
[applause]
All
>> [applause]
[cheering]
[cheering and applause]
[applause]
[applause and cheering]
>> right,
a quick update before you go. We're
doing another Tiny Desk giveaway. Enter
by September 12th, 2026, and you and a
friend could win a free trip to DC to
see a Tiny Desk concert live in person.
You even get to choose which upcoming
show you want to see. And it's
completely free to enter. Just go to
npr.org/tinyes
giveaway. [music] Entering is completely
free, but you can get more entries by
snagging some limited edition Tiny Desk
merch or by making a special donation to
the NPR network. Learn more and enter
today at npr.org/tinyes
giveaway.